Okay, so let's say I have a little bit
more complicated data. Remember I said
that everything stores as a string. So
what happens when I try and store my
data? So if I go to local storage and I
set an item and we'll call it um my data
and um I'll store this object that I've
created. If I save that and I come over
to the running site um
and I look at my application, I can see
Oh, I need to reload the page.
Oh, my live server is not running. It
would help if I ran that. Okay. So if we
come over to our page and we inspect it
and we look at the application in local
storage can see that my data is storing
object object. Well that is not very
helpful. Um what it did is it tried to
take our object and convert it into a
string. It didn't know how to do that.
So it just said okay it's an object.
Let's just store the text object. The
problem is when we try and convert this
back we can't convert it back into the
object. We have lost all of our
information. So if we want to store our
object, we first have to convert it to a
string ourselves. So to do that, what we
can do is we can use the JSON tool. So
we'll say JSON dot stringify
and then we give it the information.
What this does is it takes our
information and turns this into a string
that we can access. So I could say let
um my value equal JSON.stringify.
And then here we'll set my data equal to
my value.
Now if we come over, you can see that it
put in text the curly braces and then
the keys and then the values and it's
all there in an object. Well, that's
great. Now we can get it out. So um what
I'm going to do is I'm going to come
over here to the console and I'm going
to say local storage.get item. And the
item I want to get is my data.
And you can see it comes back as a
string. Because it's a string, I cannot
access it like an object. So I cannot
say let my new value equal local
storage.get item my data.
I cannot say my new value.name name
because if I do it's undefined because a
string doesn't have a property
calledame.
If we want to get this back out and turn
it back into an object then we have to
use the JSON tool again. So coming back
over here let's say I wanted to get it
out. I could say console.log
and then I'll use the JSON tool and then
I'll say parse. Parse takes in a JSON
string and converts it into an object.
So we can say go to local storage and
get an item out. The item that we want
to get is my data and then we want to
parse it and log it. So now if we come
over we can see that it logs out an
object and we can then access the
attributes of this object just like we
would